Bharath Kumar S

Mobile Development Team Lead

About Me

Hello! I'm Bharath Kumar. I am passionate about Mobile development and Back-end development. Having 6+ years of experience as Senior Mobile development. To be an expert on software development, facing challenges in my working environment and work for mutual development of company and myself.

Age

28 Barathkumar1010@gmail.com Email

Phone +91 9566977555 Address 39,HAK ROAD,

CHINNACHOKKIKULAM MADURAI, TAMIL NADU 625002

Professional Skills

Swift UI Swift Objective-c React JS Android Java **React Native**

Work Experience

Team Lead at Equitas Technologies

Oct, 2021 - Present

Gathering the Business requirements, and delegating tasks for the team to achieving daily, weekly, and monthly goals. Liaising with team members, business team, and customer to ensure the product feature is completed with the standard. And updating work schedules and performing troubleshooting based on the project requirement. Performing the Maintenance activity of the product after post-deployment.

Senior Mobile Developer at Falconnect Technologies

June, 2016 - Sept, 2020

Interacting with the UI designer for Mobile app design and Web app. Delegating the tasks to the peers and developing the end-product. Maintaining code reusability throughout the product life-cycle. Perform the Unit testing, SIT, assisting for UAT. Then Publishing the mobile app to the App Store and play store. Maintaining the mobile after publishing to Appstore and Play store .

I have been responsible for developing the UI Design for mobile apps. Integration of the API from the

iOS Developer at Arcus InfoTech

April, 2014 - July, 2016

Backend. Publishing the mobile app to the App store. Maintaining the mobile after publishing to Appstore.

Education

Bachelor of Computer Science from Nehru Institute of Technology , Coimbatore 2010 - 2014

2008 - 2010

Higher Secondary from Le Chatelier School, Madurai

Project Details

WowTruck at Equitas Technologies React Native, Java, Swift

The Wowtruck platform has the best drivers who provide superior customer service at affordable rates.

Wowtruck is the only app that provides guaranteed quotes for booking mini trucks from point to point. Choose the pickup and drop points, get a guaranteed quote and pay exactly the same amount on completion of the load.

WowTruck Driver at Equitas Technologies React Native, Java.

The Wowtruck Driver is an app which connects the customer and truck driver with affordable rates for both. Drive whenever you want. Partnership with Wowtruck will bring the tools you need to succeed.

This app helps in connecting the wowtruck field officers with the ops team and coordinating the customer and transporters leads with meeting and updates. Hpft users also help wowtruck platform in

WowTruck HPFT (High Performance Field Team) at Equitas Technologies

getting the transporters for different bookings.

PHP- Yii2 framework, Mysql. Wowtruck is a tech based logistics platform which provides simplified and cost effective last mile connectivity to customers as well as higher earning potential for truck drivers. This project contains

Wowtruck Admin at Equitas Technologies

mobile apps like wow truck driver app, customer app through this connect and service customers efficiently.

SFAD at Falconnect Technologies

SFAD is a Success factor to the Active Directory. We shall get the employee details from the Success

Factor and we need to process and vaildaitly the CSV file and store the values in the SQL - Server and the Windows Active Directory using the LDAP connection. We have used the windows scheduler to run the

. Net framework 4.0, Window Application, C#

.exe file without any manual action.

OSRAM Sensorat Falconnect Technologies Swift, Java, IOT. OSRAM Sensor is used to accurately measure your pulse and heart beat zone with BLE sensor Device.

similarly to pulse oximeters, detecting the change and to provide accurate heart beat measurements graph (similar to ECG / EKG / Cardiograph) - see every heartbeat and BPM.

Monitor blood circulation with an accurate heart health monitor (similar to ECG or EKG). Functions

Tumotorizado is an application of transferring the user valuable goods from one point to another as fast as possible. We have developed a technological tool observing the specific needs of customers linked to each other. It is a contract based traditional service of messaging and charging. It is advance model of

Tumotorizado at Falconnect Technologies

zhipcode and utilized in specific zone. The app completely monitors the messengers and their location for the official records.

DealerPlus at Falconnect Technologies Swift.

DMS app is specifically designed for a group of community. Through the application the user can showcase their own cars and also be able to manage their inventory funding details. Dealers can purchase the car listed in the application. Dealers can also avail funding for the specific car purchased through this application.

Swift

Zhipcode – Messenger at Falconnect Technologies Objective- C.

Zhipcode is an application of "express messaging" that connects consumers, independent messengers

and stores as fast as possible. We have developed technological tools observing the specific needs of customers linked to each of our business segments. For their private clients and companies we develop a mobile application that serves to contract traditional services of messaging and charges.

Mopro Direct Connect at Falconnect Technologies Xamarin Android. Mopro Direct Connect is an application used for Mopro Client. Using this application the client changes the things which they have to change things like design, image, text or button. In application we have

used voice recognition and VOIP for contacting the client.

Cargoji - Book a Mini Truck in India at Falconnect Technologies Objective- C. Cargoji is a revolutionary new improvement to Logistics systems in India logistics is a closed circuit with low supply and high fluctuating demand. In order to bridge this gap, Cargoji is providing a platform for all

the customers to hire a mini truck to meet them on demand logistics needs.

proposition to improve the Logistics services in our cities and grow trucking.

Cargoji - Driver at Falconnect Technologies Objective- C. Cargoji is providing a platform for all the customers to hire a mini truck to meet them on demand logistics needs. By tying up with local businesses and transport operators, Cargoji has created a Win-win

Bharath Kumar